[Music]
menopause is characterized by a decrease
in estrogen which triggers the
uncomfortable symptoms of hot flushes
night sweats sleep disturbances and
vaginal dryness among these menopausal
symptoms hot flushes also known as hot
flashes are reported by many women to be
the most bothersome
i already summarized the available
evidence on the role of soy
phytoestrogens to alleviate those
symptoms
here's the latest meta-analysis although
the balance of evidence point to soy
benefits the individual study results
are all over the place yes some studies
show 20 30 even 40 better than control
but some showed no effect
this is something that's been noted by
the professional societies like the
american college of ob gyns yes these
supplements may work but the evidence is
so inconsistent
this may be partly because the
supplements used were extracted from
different parts of the soybean
maybe it would be better if they just
use soy foods rather than supplements
the dosing would be about two servings
of traditional soy foods a day like two
cups of soy milk which is what you see
older women in japan doing
who have some of the lowest reported
rates of hot flashes in the world
but even the studies on soy foods as
opposed to supplements have had
conflicting results
why all the inconsistency it may have to
do with our gut bacteria
people who eat foods made from soybeans
which have these health health-promoting
isoflavones tend to have lower rates of
a variety of chronic diseases
so we can garner this protection by
eating more soy foods right
well it may be a little more complicated
than that
there are certain gut bacteria that can
convert isoflavones in soy into a
potentially even more beneficial
compound called equal
not all individuals can make this
conversion though because not all
individuals have the specific types of
good bacteria in their gut that do it
so there's two types of people in the
world equal producers and equal
non-producers
depending on their gut flora
and so this may help account for the
variations and health benefits we see in
clinical studies it may help explain why
some people seem to benefit from soy
more than others
for example in the study i covered
before about how soy milk appears to
prevent bone loss in the spines of
post-menopausal women
if you split the women into equal
producers and non-producers soy did work
in non-equal producers but seem to work
even better in the women whose gut
bacteria is able to take the soy to the
next level
the more equal japanese women make from
the soy they eat the fewer menopausal
symptoms they may have
some studies suggest equal producing men
may get less prostate cancer if that's
the case maybe we should look into
improving the intestinal environment to
enable equal production
only a minority of the western adult
population is able to produce equal
though almost every other animal species
appears to produce it no problem in fact
that's how it got its name it's named
equal because it was first discovered in
horses
but interestingly horses during the
summer not winter
because that's when their gut bacteria
had access to the phytoestrogens in
clover
that was our first clue equal was made
from plants
if you're not mr ed though can you take
someone who doesn't make equal and
convert them into an equal producer
certainly you can do the reverse
excessive use of antibiotics can wipe
out your good bugs
but how can you acquire the right good
bugs suggested strategies include
dietary alteration or probiotics the
standard probiotic regimens don't seem
to help so how about dietary alteration
well about half of japanese and korean
individuals can produce equal
but only
as low as one in seven americans
maybe it's because more soy is eaten in
asia and that would make sense if you
eat a lot of soy you may foster the
growth of bacteria in your gut that can
digest soy
but a month of soy isoflavone supplement
exposure didn't seem to convert
non-producers into producers
but just two weeks of drinking three
glasses of soy milk a day was able to
convert three of six women into
producers for example this woman started
out not making any at all or maybe a
little bump between hours 50 and 60 but
after two weeks of drinking soy milk
when they had her drink some more she
had nice equal spikes
it didn't work for all women though and
when they tried the same experiment in
men nothing happened
back to the drawing board is there any
group of westerners that have high equal
production rates that may offer a clue
vegetarians have among the highest equal
production rates ever recorded more than
four times as likely to be equal
producers as their non-vegetarian
counterparts
the question is why they don't think
it's because of the soy given the
conflicting soy data
maybe it's because they're eating more
prebiotics like fiber
or maybe dietary fat intake decreases
the capacity of gut flora to make equal
or maybe it has something to do with
cholesterol intake
analyzing the diets of equal producers
they do seem more likely to be eating
more carbs plant protein and fiber
but researchers have tried giving people
fiber supplements along with soy but
that didn't seem to work
whatever it is about those eating
plant-based diets they may soon be the
only remaining majority equal producers
as asian populations continue
to westernize their diets
[Music]
foreign